Inventory of the James A. Bill Papers 1940-2003
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
- The Eagle and the Lion Research, 1941-1986, bulk 1951-1979
  - Chapter 7 of The Eagle and the Lion - Energy (7)
    - (7, 4)
      - (7, 4, 1)
        - Natural Gas (7, 4, 1, 3)
          - (7, 4, 1, 3)
            - Natural gas- a hedge against energy crunch by Bijan Mossavar-Rahmani in Kayhan International, 12/10/1977 (7, 4, 1, 3)
            - Construction of new IGAT line is on schedule [Kayhan International?], 3/15/1977 (7, 4, 1, 3)
            - NIGC plans $2b gas expansion projects KI, 1/13/1977 (7, 4, 1, 3)
          Subseries 4: Petrochemicals
        - Petrochemicals (7, 4, 1)
          - (7, 4, 1, 5)
            - $2 billion complex meet in KI 12/20/77: Iran Japan Petrochemical Company; Turning Iran into the land of petrochemicals by Hushang Nemazee in KI 6/20/77; Iran takes another massive step in petrochemicals in Events No. 26 9/23/77; A New Iran raises its towers on Persian Gulf in KI 10/23/77 (7, 4, 1, 5)
            - Where is the basis for Iran industrialization? by Jagdish Sharma in KI, 4/8/1978 (7, 4, 1, 5)
            - Building to scale of Asia KI, 3/18/1978 (7, 4, 1, 5)
            - Shahpur chemical plant capacity raised 250pc KI, 3/19/1978 (7, 4, 1, 5)
            - NPC plans to pour $3.5b. into petrochemicals KI, 6/26/1977 (7, 4, 1, 5)
            - Petrochemicals To Be Nation Biggest Industry Kayhan International, 7/18/1976 (7, 4, 1, 5)
          Subseries 5: Other Forms of Energy/Industrialization: Nuclear Power, Coal, Copper, Steel, etc.
        - Other Forms of Energy/Industrialization: Nuclear Power, Coal, Copper, Steel, etc. (7, 4, 1, 5)
          - (7, 4, 1, 5, 6)
            - Energy in Iran and the case for nuclear power Kayhan International 2/6/78 [ON BACK OF THIS ARTICLE IS ANOTHER ONE: New increases likely in prices of petrol UNDER GAS HEADING] (7, 4, 1, 5, 6)
            - Iran steel mills struggle to catch up with demand by Ralph Joseph in K. International, 5/2/1978 (7, 4, 1, 5, 6)
            - Monarch welcomes major new coal finds KI, 3/15/1978 (7, 4, 1, 5, 6)
            - Copper complex nearly finished Kayhan International, 1/23/1978 (7, 4, 1, 5, 6)
            - To export or not-The industrialist dilemma by Farhad Karani KI, 6/28/1977 (7, 4, 1, 5, 6)
            - Evolving an action program for housing projects: Timing the Loans in KI, 4/5/1977 (7, 4, 1, 5, 6)
            - Providing Shah with A-power: France Scores;Iran less likely to pick US for providing new energy by Jim Browning in CSM, 10/12/1976 (7, 4, 1, 5, 6)
        Subseries 2: Bill Butler Folder
      - Bill Butler Folder (7, 4, 2)
        - (7, 4, 2)
          - Handwritten notes (7, 4, 2)
          - Aide Memoir from Butler, Chairman Executive Committee, International Commission of Jurists to Amir Abas Hoveyda, Minister of Court, Iran (7, 4, 2)
          - Memorandum on Private Audience with Shah of Iran, 5/30/1977 (7, 4, 2)
          - Letter to Butler from William Sullivan, 12/11/1977 (7, 4, 2)
          - Memorandum to Shah from Butler- human rights (7, 4, 2)
          - Human Rights in Iran: Hearing before the Subcommittee on International Organizations of the Committee on International Relations House of Representatives, 10/26/1977 (7, 4, 2)
        Subseries 3: Arms Sales to Iran/Iran Foreign Policy
      - Arms Sales to Iran/Iran Foreign Policy (7, 4, 3)
          Subseries 1: Arms Sales to Iran
        - Arms Sales to Iran (7, 4, 3, 1)
          - (7, 4, 3, 1, 8)
            - Iran Cuts Arms Spending by John K. Cooley in CSM (7, 4, 3, 1, 8)
            - Strong defense build-up is source of stability for Iran by Abbas Amirie in KI, 10/19/1976 (7, 4, 3, 1, 8)
            - Despite Huge Outlays, Iran Forces are Short of Security Arms by Drew Middleton in New York Times, 7/14/1975 (7, 4, 3, 1, 8)
            - US Offers Iran 10 of its Costliest Radar Planes NYT, 12/16/1975 (7, 4, 3, 1, 8)
            - Iran Packs a New Punch by Edward Cochran (7, 4, 3, 1, 8)
            - Iran Irritated: Shah warns Congress not to stop arms sales or Iran would cut off oil in CSM, 3/16/1976 (7, 4, 3, 1, 8)
            - Iran May Reduce US Arms Buying by John W. Finney in NYT, 2/4/1976 (7, 4, 3, 1, 8)
            - Study Finds Iran Dependent on US in Using Weapons by Leslie H. Gelb in NYT, 8/1/1976 (7, 4, 3, 1, 8)
            - US Arms Sales to Iran are Seen as Out of Control Wall Street Journal, 8/2/1976 (7, 4, 3, 1, 8)
            - Shah Cautions US Against Arms Cut by Bernard Gwertzman in NYT, 8/7/1976 (7, 4, 3, 1, 8)
            - Iran and Britain Plan Arms Deal By Eric Pace in NYT, 8/11/1976 (7, 4, 3, 1, 8)
            - Iran Said to Put Stress on Barter: Talks on Exchange of US Planes for Oil Reported NYT, 8/12/1976 (7, 4, 3, 1, 8)
            - Iran + oil + guns by Joseph C. Harsch in CSM, 8/17/1976 (7, 4, 3, 1, 8)
            - The Military Buildup in Iran by Ray Vicker in Wall Street Journal, 9/1/1976 (7, 4, 3, 1, 8)
            - Why US sells arms to the Shah by Alvin J. Cottrell in CSM, 9/15/1976 (7, 4, 3, 1, 8)
            - The Department of State News Release Sale of F-16s to Iran: statement by Philip C. Habib, 9/19/1976 (7, 4, 3, 1, 8)
          - (7, 4, 3, 1, 9)
            - US arms sales top $13 billion Christian Science Monitor [CSM], 10/4/1978 (7, 4, 3, 1, 9)
            - Military buildup key to safeguarding oil KI, 2/27/1977 (7, 4, 3, 1, 9)
            - Iran shows way in army aviation by Col. Obel Wells in KI, 5/23/1977 (7, 4, 3, 1, 9)
            - Iran Vast Purchases of Weaponry Strain Ability of Country to Absorb It All by Eric Page in NYT, 1/5/1977 (7, 4, 3, 1, 9)
            - Arms-sale pattern cited in The Stars and Stripes, 10/8/1977 (7, 4, 3, 1, 9)
            - US takes a second look at arms deals with Iran in Events, no. 18, 6/3/1977 (7, 4, 3, 1, 9)
            - No Concern Over Iran Arms: Vance by Raji Samghabadi in KI, 5/14/1977 (7, 4, 3, 1, 9)
          - (7, 4, 3, 1, 10)
            - Arms and the Shah: The Rise and Fall of the Surrogate Strategy by Michael T. Klare in The Progressive August 1979 v.43, n.8 (7, 4, 3, 1, 10)
            - Prospective Sale of Airborne Warning And Control System (AWACS) Aircraft to Iran: Hearings before the Subcommittees on International Security and Scientific Affairs and on Europe and the Middle East of the Committee on International Relations 6/29, 7/19, 7/21 1977 (7, 4, 3, 1, 10)
            - Small collection of handwritten notes: Program Summary about aircraft purchases by Iran (7, 4, 3, 1, 10)
          Subseries 2: Iran Foreign Policy
        - Iran Foreign Policy (7, 4, 3, 2)
          - (7, 4, 3, 2, 11)
            - Modernizing Iran Seeks Dominant Role in Region by Juan de Onis in New York Times (7, 4, 3, 2, 11)
            - Egypt and Iran may shift Middle East balance by Joseph Fitchett in CSM, 12/23/1974 (7, 4, 3, 2, 11)
            - Iran development calls on India: Persian Gulf security blueprinted-South Asia seen as market for exports by Mohan Ram in CSM, 8/21/1975 (7, 4, 3, 2, 11)
            - Iran: peacekeeper or empire builder? by Russell Brines in CSM, 8/22/1975 (7, 4, 3, 2, 11)
            - Iranian Navy growing as an Indian Ocean power by Richard Burt in CSM, 8/22/1975 (7, 4, 3, 2, 11)
            - The Shah Big Stick by Rowland Evans and Robert Novak in San Juan Star, 11/10/1973 (7, 4, 3, 2, 11)
            - Shah irked at criticism in US press: Admits 2,000 Iranian Troops Fighting in Oman by Majid Namvar Intercontinental Press, 1/27/1975 (7, 4, 3, 2, 11)
            - Iran- Self-appointed guardian of the gulf by Dana Adams Schmidt in CSM, 1/29/1975 (7, 4, 3, 2, 11)
            - Why Shah builds vast military power: Iran leader quest for global security in CSM, 2/12/1975 (7, 4, 3, 2, 11)
            - Iran Said to Vow Defense of Oman By Eric Pace in New York Times, 2/3/1975 (7, 4, 3, 2, 11)
            - Iran Flexes its Muscles by Ray Vicker in Wall Street Journal, 7/23/1975 (7, 4, 3, 2, 11)
            - Shah of Iran Uses Oman to Train Armed Forces by Eric Pace in New York Times, 1/25/1976 (7, 4, 3, 2, 11)
        Subseries 4: US Considers War in Middle East
      - US Considers War in Middle East (7, 4)
        - (7, 4, 12)
          - Fire drill for the Carter Doctrine: The Armed Forces Gear Up for Desert War by Michael T. Klare August 1979 in Mother Jones [?] (7, 4, 12)
          - US wary of military solution to oil supply CSM, 7/16/1979 (7, 4, 12)
          - Report Says Risks Would Rule Out US Armed Action in Persian Gulf by Drew Middleton in New York Times, 7/14/1979 (7, 4, 12)
          - US Earmarks Force for Fast Deployment in Mideast by Drew Middleton in New York Times, 4/20/1979 (7, 4, 12)
        Subseries 5: Sadegh Ghotbzadeh
      - Sadegh Ghotbzadeh (7, 4, 5)
        - (7, 4, 5, 13)
          - 4 Years Here Stormy for Ghotbzadeh by Donnel Nunes in Washington Post, 12/13/1979 (7, 4, 5, 13)
          - - The State of Iran Today by Sadegh Ghotbzadeh in Georgetown University Courier vol. XI, n. 7 April-May 1963 (7, 4, 5, 13)
        Subseries 6: President Jimmy Carter and First Lady Rosalynn Carter and Administration
      - President Jimmy Carter and First Lady Rosalynn Carter and Administration (7, 4, 6)
        - (7, 4, 6, 14)
          - First Lady from Plains by Rosalynn Carter (Boston: Houghton Mifflin 1984): Chapter 11: Iran and the Beginning of the End (7, 4, 6, 14)
          - Assessing a Presidency in Time 8/18/1980 [the Carter Presidency Issue] (7, 4, 6, 14)
          - The Enigmatic President by Hedley Donovan in Time, 5/6/1985 (7, 4, 6, 14)
          - Brzezinski- Activist Seeker of World Order LA Times 1/24/1977 [From Bill Box III] (7, 4, 6, 14)
          - Bill Moyers Journal: transcription of Voices on Iran aired 5/1/1980 (7, 4, 6, 14)
          - Shahanshah, Carter exchange messages KI, 4/11/1977 (7, 4, 6, 14)
          - The Mideast Observer vol. II, no.4 February 15, 1979 + interview with Carter about Shah (7, 4, 6, 14)
        Subseries 7: Ibrahim Yazdi
      - Ibrahim Yazdi (7, 4)
        - (7, 4, 15)
          - 3 typed short articles from the Information Bank on Yazdi, the Shah contribution to Nixon campaign, and closeness of Shah with Kissinger and other American officials (7, 4, 15)
          - Yadzi: Capitalism Kills and Ramadan Bans: Attacking Music and the Press in Time 8/6/197? (7, 4, 15)
        Subseries 8: General Robert E. Huyser
      - General Robert E. Huyser (7, 4, 8)
        - (7, 4, 8, 16)
          - General Denies His Role Was to Usher Out Shah by Howard Silber in Omaha World Herald 8/7/1980; letter from Victor T. Le Vine to Col. John D. Williams on interviewing Gen. Huyser with handwritten note to Bill on bottom (7, 4, 8, 16)
          - Huyser says US coup against Shah planned in Iran Times vol. XI no. 35, 11/13/1981 (7, 4, 8, 16)
          - General Huyser Mission to Iran, January 1979: Hearing Before the Subcommittee on Europe and the Middle East of the Committee on Foreign Affairs House of Representatives, 6/9/1981 (7, 4, 8, 16)
        Subseries 9: Black Friday
      - Black Friday (7, 4, 9)
        - (7, 4, 9, 17)
          - Did Carter OK the Shah get tough policy? by Jean Gueyras in The Guardian, 10/15/1978 (7, 4, 9, 17)
          - Liberalization the main casualty by Jean Gueyras in The Guardian, 9/17/1978 (7, 4, 9, 17)
          - Iran: Carrot and Stick in Newsweek, 9/25/1978 (7, 4, 9, 17)
          - Black Friday: Martyrs Square- Sept. 8- Tehran Resistance vol.5 no.7 October 1978 (7, 4, 9, 17)
          - It Was Very Close interview with Shah by Paul Martin in Newsweek (7, 4, 9, 17)
        Subseries 10: Other Information Re: Chapter 7 of The Eagle and the Lion
      - Other Information Re: Chapter 7 of The Eagle and the Lion (7, 4, 10)
        - (7, 4, 10, 18)
          - Cover in Farsi with US presidential seal and zipper: 5/4/78 memorandum on Iran: Overall US-Iran relations are excellent (7, 4, 10, 18)
          - Anti-American Demonstration: Iranian students of Sports University staged demonstration in presence of American wrestlers in Iran [THIS ARTICLE IS ON BACK OF Natural gas- a hedge against energy crunch ARTICLEï¿½"UNDER GAS HEADING] (7, 4, 10, 18)
          - Iran: Is the Shah Pushing Too Fast? by James Bill in CSM (7, 4, 10, 18)
        - (7, 4, 10, 19)
          - Iran: US Foreign Policy and the Tradition of Persian Statecraft in Orbis Vol.23 No.2 Summer 1979 by Adda B. Bozeman pp. 387-402 (7, 4, 10, 19)
          - Iran Diary, 1980 by Oriana Fallaci in The New Republic vol. 182, no. 19, issue 3409 May 10, 1980 (7, 4, 10, 19)
            With note by Bill saying "Good description of Bani-Sadr"
          - Who Lost Iran: Revising Revisionist History by Stephen Cohen in [Washington Post?] (7, 4, 10, 19)
          - William P. Bundy Foreign Policy in the 1980 Campaign Foreign Affairs Fall 1979 11-23 [From Bill Box III] (7, 4, 10, 19)
          - The Pride and the Fall: Iran 1974-1979 by Anthony Parsons, British Ambassador to Iran (London: Jonathon Cape, 1984) Chapter 7: Retrospect (7, 4, 10, 19)
        - (7, 4, 10, 20)
          - Iran Who Who: A, N, F, M (7, 4, 10, 20)
          - 51 page paper by unknown author on Iran, divided into parts- Part 1: The Iranian Political Elite: An Analytic Profile Part 2: Political Opposition in Iran Part 3: The Future of Iran: Political Alternatives and Economic Policy (7, 4, 10, 20)
        - (7, 4, 10, 21)
          - Issue of Kayhan International 4/12/78 with several articles marked by Bill: New emphasis on exports will kick some life into Iranian business; The barren womb of red and black reaction; Princess Slams Chasm Between Rich and Poor; National Unity First Priority- Ansary (7, 4, 10, 21)
          - Views and Thoughts Red and Black Colonization in Iran by Ahmad Rashidi Motlaq, translated by Abbass Manafy: transcription of article in English with photocopy of it in Farsi (7, 4, 10, 21)
          - However Slight, an Opposition Does Exist in Iran by Paul Hofman in NYT, 4/2/1978 (7, 4, 10, 21)
        - (7, 4, 10, 22)
          - Hakim- JB 9/22/1970- Bakeri: one page typed on Susari, Eqbal and Bakeri [notes from interview?] (7, 4, 10, 22)
          - Typed note from Jim thanking Jim for diplomatic lists and two sources, 2/1/1985 (7, 4, 10, 22)
          - Planned amendments to rules of military court KI, 6/16/1977 (7, 4, 10, 22)
          - M. Montazari Accusations against Bazarzan [?] (CIA!): article in Tehran Mosavar [?] 29 Tir 1358, p. 10: IN FARSI (7, 4, 10, 22)
          - - Events of the Year Twelve Months of Transition compiled by Amir Ali Afshar in Kayhan International, 3/20/1978 (7, 4, 10, 22)
    Subseries 8: Chapter 9 of The Eagle and the Lion
  - Chapter 9 of The Eagle and the Lion (8)
    - (8, 5)
        Subseries 1: Circle of Influence: Chapter 9
      - Circle of Influence: Chapter 9 (8, 5, 1)
        - (8, 5, 1)
          - Lists of Interlocking Directorates (8, 5, 1)
          - Pad with handwritten notes on who is in the Circle of Influence and Revisions for Chapter 9/10 [ from Bill Box III] (8, 5, 1)
          - Packet of various documents on William Jackson- the Shah lawyer (8, 5, 1)
          - Typed notes on books that concern men who had ties to NIOC, Rockefellers, Chase Bank (8, 5, 1)
          - Notes and articles on Former Representative John M. Murphy (8, 5, 1)
        - (8, 5, 1, 2)
          - Handwritten notes on Ralph E. Becker and others (8, 5, 1, 2)
          - Letter to Bill from John Newton with handwritten notes all around it, 9/12/1986 (8, 5, 1, 2)
          - Handwritten notes on interview with William Paul (8, 5, 1, 2)
          - The Great American Salon in Newsweek, 7/14/1980 (8, 5, 1, 2)
        - (8, 5, 1, 3)
          - Letters to Bill from Delphine Blachowicz on Zahedi, gifts and various other things (8, 5, 1, 3)
          - Various newspaper clippings on Zahedi connections, Shah and Nixon campaign (8, 5, 1, 3)
        - (8, 5, 1, 4)
          - Letters between James Bill and Rosella Howe concerning surveys conducted by Yankelovich, Skelly and White asking American influentials about Iran- Shah is mostly likely the one who paid to have surveys done (8, 5, 1, 4)
          - Various newspaper clippings on Marion Javits (8, 5, 1, 4)
        - (8, 5, 1)
          - David Lilienthal Folder: from Bill Box III (8, 5, 1)
        Subseries 2: Gift List- Mass Media
      - Gift List- Mass Media (8, 5, 2)
        - List of Great Britain News Media (8, 5, 2, 6)
        - US members of the News Media who received gifts: includes name, address, year received gift and type of gift received, pages 4-14, 16-29 (8, 5, 2, 7)
        - US members of the News Media who received gifts: includes name, address, year received gift and type of gift received, pages 32-56 (8, 5, 2)
        - US members of the News Media who received gifts: includes name, address, year received gift and type of gift received, pages 57-74, 76-82 (8, 5, 2, 9)
        - US members of the News Media who received gifts: includes name, address, year received gift and type of gift received, pages 83-107 (8, 5, 2, 10)
        - US members of the News Media who received gifts: includes name, address, year received gift and type of gift received, pages 108-135 (8, 5, 2, 11)
        - (8, 5, 2, 12)
          - Handwritten tallies on Mass Media Gift Lists (8, 5, 2, 12)
          - Various newspaper clippings on corruption in the press and journalists who took bribes (8, 5, 2, 12)
        Subseries 3: Social Webs of Influence
      - Social Webs of Influence (8, 5, 3)
        - Reza Shah Kabir University (8, 5, 3, 13)
          - New Science Ministry aides in Tehran Journal, 6/20/1974 (8, 5, 3, 13)
          - Charter for the Reza Shah Kabir University (8, 5, 3, 13)
          - Handwritten note card of Confidential Ideas (8, 5, 3, 13)
          - List of Board of Trustees of Reza Shah The Great University (8, 5, 3, 13)
          - CVs for Iranian members of the Iran-Harvard Planning Commission (8, 5, 3, 13)
          - List of Functions at RSKU that are to be Performed by an Intermediate (8, 5, 3, 13)
          - Letter from Abdol Hossein Samii to President Bok about the Iran-Harvard (8, 5, 3, 13)
          - Iran- Harvard Planning Commission: outline and info. on it (8, 5, 3, 13)
          - Letter from Samii to Dr. Peter Chase on the Iranian members of the joint commission (8, 5, 3, 13)
          - Basic Assumptions of Harvard RSKU Study (8, 5, 3, 13)
        - Newspaper Articles (8, 5, 3, 14)
          - Iran gift of $3 million to University of Chicago (8, 5, 3, 14)
          - The Shah 12 visits to Washington (8, 5, 3, 14)
          - Shah financial support of the Nixon campaign (8, 5, 3, 14)
          - Shah gives $1/4 million to Hubert Humphrey Foundation (Kissinger named chairman) (8, 5, 3, 14)
          - The Pahlavi Foundation in New York (8, 5, 3, 14)
        - (8, 5, 3, 15)
          - Zahedi: Zahedi social life in Washington (8, 5, 3, 15)
          - Iranian Folk Dancers in New York (8, 5, 3, 15)
          - Romance between Elizabeth Taylor and Zahedi (8, 5, 3, 15)
          - Persian Festival in Houston, Texas (8, 5, 3, 15)
          - American Bicentennial/Pahlavi Dynasty 50th anniversary trip to Iran including Elizabeth Taylor (8, 5, 3, 15)
          - Gifts given to US officials/journalists by Zahedi (3 articles) (8, 5, 3, 15)
          - Town Talk Busy Minister May Commute by Helicopter (Also Ansary reference) [From Bill Box III] (8, 5, 3, 15)
        - Parties (8, 5, 3, 16)
          - Party given by Shah for Nixon (8, 5, 3, 16)
          - The Shah allergy of caviar (8, 5, 3, 16)
          - President Carter dinner for the Shah (8, 5, 3, 16)
          - Party given by Zahedi in NYC attended by Empress Farah (8, 5, 3, 16)
        - Princess Ashraf (8, 5, 3, 17)
          - Party for Princess Ashraf (8, 5, 3, 17)
          - Suprise party for Princess Ashraf (8, 5, 3, 17)
        - Empress Farah (8, 5, 3, 18)
          - Empress Farah visit to the National Gallery (8, 5, 3, 18)
          - Sotheby art sales to Iranians (8, 5, 3, 18)
          - Empress Farah trip to US in 1975 (8, 5, 3, 18)
          - Farah Pahlavi Foundation (8, 5, 3, 18)
          - Empress Given Top US Award (Appeal of Conscience Award- 3 articles) (8, 5, 3, 18)
        - Kayhan International Town Talk: 10 articles (8, 5, 3, 19)
        Subseries 4: Kissinger and the Rockefellers
      - Kissinger and the Rockefellers (8, 5, 4)
        - Asylum for the Shah (8, 5, 4, 20)
          - Articles concerning the Shah entry into the US after revolution (8, 5, 4, 20)
          - Kissinger role in the Shah entry into US (8, 5, 4, 20)
          - Shah plan to buy home in New York City (8, 5, 4, 20)
          - Suit against Science by doctor who examined Shah before he was admitted to US (8, 5, 4, 20)
          - A Matter of Principle by Marvin Stone in US News and World Report 12/17/1979 (8, 5, 4, 20)
        - Kissinger (8, 5, 4, 21)
          - Carl Kotchian and corruption in Lockheed Aircraft Corp. (8, 5, 4, 21)
          - List of articles to be obtained (8, 5, 4, 21)
          - What Wrong with Henry Kissinger by Richard Falk in Princeton Alumni Weekly October 1, 1974 (8, 5, 4, 21)
          - Discussion between Kissinger and Shah about arms, nuclear technology and oil (8, 5, 4, 21)
          - The New Fourth Branch of Government L. Cooper in Manchester Guardian Weekly, 4/22/1979 (8, 5, 4, 21)
          - Kissinger consulting business- Kissinger Associates (8, 5, 4, 21)
          - Kissinger in Reagan cabinet (8, 5, 4, 21)
          - Two of the President Men (Kissinger and Alexander Haig) in Time, 4/26/1982 (8, 5, 4, 21)
          - The Reluctant Reality of Henry Kissinger by Tom Wicker in Rolling Stone, 02/21/1980 (8, 5, 4, 21)
          - Transcript of Phil Donahue show with Henry Kissinger as guest (8, 5, 4, 21)
          - Review of book The Price of Power: Kissinger in the Nixon White House (8, 5, 4, 21)
          - Kissinger trip to Tehran in the Air Force Three (8, 5, 4, 21)
          - Kissinger the Alchemist Bernard D. Nossiter in the Washington Post, 5/27/1979 (8, 5, 4, 21)
          - Kissinger and Bill Simon lucrative jobs after serving as Nixon aides (8, 5, 4, 21)
        - Chase Manhattan Bank, David Rockefeller, and Kissinger (8, 5, 4, 22)
          - 6 handwritten brief descriptions on NYT articles on Rockefeller in 1974, 1976 (8, 5, 4, 22)
          - The secret contents of the missing Rockefeller file in Events No. 13, 3/25/1977 (8, 5, 4, 22)
          - Chase Manhattan Ties to the Shah Dan Morgan in Washington Post, 11/16/1979 (8, 5, 4, 22)
          - Shah and Rockefeller Planning a Small War to Retake Iran in Spotlight, 12/24/1979 (8, 5, 4, 22)
          - Rockefeller leaves Chase Manhattan (8, 5, 4, 22)
          - The Change at David Bank in Time, 9/1/1980 (8, 5, 4, 22)
          - Chase David Rockefeller Discusses The Shah, Politics, Personal Wealth in Wall Street Journal, 3/27/1981 (8, 5, 4, 22)
          - Hostages for the Chase Manhattan L. J. Davis in Penthouse December 1980 (8, 5, 4, 22)
          - Kissinger suit against Penthouse for the article of Rockefeller and Chase Manhattan (8, 5, 4, 22)
        - Nelson Rockefeller (8, 5, 4, 23)
          - Rockefeller Brothers Fund for philanthropy and research sets up new research on US future- Kissinger will head the study (8, 5, 4, 23)
          - Vice President Nelson A. Rockefeller warned yesterday... in NYT, 3/27/1976 (8, 5, 4, 23)
          - Shahanshah has revealed world energy solution- Rockefeller in Kayhan International, 4/3/1976 (8, 5, 4, 23)
          - VP Nelson Rockefeller; The Information Bank: 4 articles in NYT on VP Nelson Rockefeller- his trip and his meeting with Shah on Kish Island (8, 5, 4, 23)
          - Rockefeller gives a report on trip by Philip Shabecoff in NYT, 4/23/1976 (8, 5, 4, 23)
          - Rockefeller Talks With Shah in NYT (8, 5, 4, 23)